[Music]
Inar, nice to see you again. Welcome,
Adon. Pleasure being here for a second
time. Really excited to see how this
community evolved. Yeah, totally. Are
you Are you joining us from Israel
again? Is that right? Yeah, that's
correct. I'm moving to New York uh late
July. Oh, nice. Congrats. Congrats. Fun.
You'll be uh I I live in Boulder,
Colorado in the US, so I'll be able to
see you see you states side. I'll get
there when I get to later on the career.
Yes. That's awesome. Well, thanks so
much again. Really, really excited to to
hear what you've uh got to say. And so I
want to jump off stage here so I can
listen in and and learn from your your
latest uh rendition of what you've been
learning on the agent side. So um let's
get your slides up and and take things
away. So continuing guy, I'm going I'm
in the tomorrow track, right? Although
at COD uh we very focus on today and
tomorrow. I might mix a bit of some of
what Cotto is doing today. But I am here
to entertain for what's coming tomorrow
and I will continue from where Guy left
it but I will iterate it a bit in my uh
point of view. So Edmar Friedman the CEO
and co-founder of Kodto formerly known
as Kodium AI there are few kodiums each
one took his its path and I'm here to
talk from code completion to multi-agent
workflows where I'm going to try to
convince although I don't think it's
that like already futuristic saying that
that multi- aent workflows is is the way
to go. So let let's start. So if we're
looking on the AI for devs world uh and
on the x-axis we're taking the knob and
and the enterprise developers like
that's maybe the one that cares the most
about like for example quality and all
maybe and and generation and creation
then I think that gen 1.0 was the
autocomplete moment. It's actually quite
uh old quotequote uh with players from
more than nine years ago, but I think it
had a moment with the copilot or by
GitHub copilot. And I think what we saw
is that people that already know uh how
to how to develop, they really like this
autocomplete, they could achieve more.
And maybe like the extreme the right
side like maybe autocomplete was a bit
annoying for them uh for a long while
but the majority of professional it
actually helped them to achieve more and
then uh came uh gen 2.0 which was the
chat and even 2.1 uh uh gentic chat and
then I think like people started to love
the the you know the technology the user
experience etc and I think also that
less professional people could achieve
much more before that when you had the
autocomplete maybe English to code was
already possible but less than what you
can achieve with the chat or oric chat
And I do think for some of course I'm
generalizing for some of the
professionals actually the the the idea
that you get from chat you get a feature
actually introduces some risk or some
inefficiency you get a lot of code and
you need to review it etc again I'm not
talking about the future right now I'm
talking about the current state of uh
intelligence coding let's call it like
that right um and then I think what
we're going to See, very soon we're
seeing already early birds. We're seeing
early adopters, companies that are and
and products and open source. We're
coming with the Gen
3.0 3.0 and that's end to end workflows
and I'm going to talk about it a bit uh
later on what it means. Okay. And I
believe that we're seeing gamecher
moment in intelligent software
development. Basically the autocomplete
moment in a chat and agentic were let's
say amplifiers for developers in a way
of their assisting you and once you're
moving to end to end then basically
they're becoming uh uh team members it's
still really really early and we're
going to elaborate about that a bit. So
the phases if I if I summarize first we
saw like ID plugins right and then what
we saw is the ID forks right you all
know what I'm talking about and if you
what I'm trying to say here is that
they're all assisting you where you
usually write your code and when we're
talking about endtoend workflows then
we're also talking about AI across the
CLC and that's where I believe uh you
will see companies that are and products
etc that building for for the end to end
workflows, not necessarily only on in
the ID. I'm not going to talk too much
about COD in that respect, but chainless
plug, this is exactly where where we
focus at. Okay. Now, I didn't mention
here like vibe coding. I'm I feel
ashamed like I'm talking for I don't
know like four minutes or so and I
didn't mention that, right? So, let's
talk about it a bit. Uh Andre Karpati,
I'm sure that you're you're all aware of
uh he coined the term vibe coding.
Actually, maybe it's weird for some of
us. It wasn't that long ago. And you can
see for example that it strongly
correlates to uh the Sonet Sonet latest
version like 3.5 coming out out and then
like tools like cursor worked really
well. But then there's other things that
happened. I'm not sure if you're hearing
uh uh the the video. Um so I'm going to
narrate it a bit. So we we saw some uh
like um let's say pushbacks or
interesting opinions about what's vibe
coding. So for those that are not
familiar with v coding, I don't think
anyone is here, but those that want to
entertain themselves a bit, let me
narrate this video. So basically I'm a
developer, right? And I'm thinking where
am I in the code? I want to develop a
new feature, right? I'm Alice. And then
here I got to my rescue an AI an AI
assistant. And I'm saying, "Oh my god,
here is an AI for developers. Uh, and I
want help to I don't know like create my
feature." And I'm asking for for an I to
help me with that.
Now,
interestingly, the developer is asking
where to go and the cat is the asking
where do you want to get to, right? And
the developer is asking saying back, I
just want to complete the feature,
right? So, the AI is saying, so it
doesn't matter how where where you go,
let me take you through one path, one
way to to get to your destination of
completing the future. all all paths
flee to Rome or the feature it doesn't
matter for you developers I'll take you
through one but by the way if you really
like to know you just got a bug there
and there okay so that's like like vibe
coding and with with that like uh let's
say feeling uh we move on to
some posts on on X and and LinkedIn that
I noticed more recently saying okay with
two developers using vibe coding you can
do like 10x 5x sorry 5x 10x maybe 25x
productivity but also 25x uh technical
depth and for me it was shocking I
thought it's a bit exa
exaggerating I do remind you that like
it does matter which kind of a developer
you are probably and like as I mentioned
maybe some of the enterprise or most
professional developers don't think that
vibe coding is a good idea and maybe
that's like one example of such touch
and I try to check my own network and
and I did on X and in and LinkedIn uh
posts and I noticed that most people
think that there is gain of productivity
5x which is amazing for like two
developers and the technical depth maybe
I'm not clear here but it could be
between like just the same that it was
before if it's 2x or maybe 2x more than
than you would expect uh but the
majority are saying that there is
productivity although gain although I
didn't give an option for not uh but
also a technical depth that that is
growing and by the way on LinkedIn it's
was a bit worse uh on towards technical
depth and here is like my understanding
like like understanding of of the
situation the thing is that with simple
software like if you're starting a
simple game uh from scratch what's
simple is actually the border of what
what simple is is moving it's a moving
target but what's simple uh oh sorry but
for simple software like code generation
is is all you need. That's the tip of
the iceberg. But underneath when you're
talking about heavyduty enterprise
software, you need also to relate to
maintainability, code coverage,
compliance, testing, best practices,
etc. Dealing with scale, don't repeat
yourself. That's very important concept
for heavy duty software which is really
hard to to get for example with VI code
or with chats chat interface. That's the
claim of of this like looking for
tomorrow's se session. Let me try to
give another point of view for for that.
Um I think that the most basic s part of
the SDLC is like I want to plan my code
what I the feature more accurately and
the technical spec and then I want to
write the code and then or generate the
code and
then probably I also want to verify its
correctness and its standards scale etc.
So that's the testing and review part.
We divide that into what we call the
blue team at KOD. We divided to the blue
team and the red team. Like blue team is
like where most code generation put
their efforts and and and focus and and
with amazing UXUI and technology we all
got fall in love with with using that.
Now there is a small illusion here is
that plan and writing code is all you
need. Actually vibe coding to some
extent is like iterating over these two
uh when you're developing a new feature.
It works works really well. It also
works with existing code, but it works
really well when you you have nothing
from scratch for example. But the thing
is in reality, especially in heavy duty,
you're doing a lot of changing feature,
refactoring, fixing a bug, and you also
care that even a new feature would be
tested and review. And that the red team
is something that we're claiming that
we're going to see uh tomorrow. Uh when
I'm saying tomorrow, I literally mean
like the next half of of 2020 uh the
next half the second half of 2025 as
well as 2026 being the next like
exciting uh uh let's say uh value prop
position of of of AI to for software
developers. Now the thing is that I
think a lot of the the testing and
review they need to have really high
precision. Basically, I claim if you
vibe code them, then basically you
didn't really like uh uh did the you
didn't really complete the purpose of
the red team and and having workflows
doing the red team is very important.
Again, I'm going to obviously cover it
in in a second in like in the next few
minutes. So, what could be workflows? It
could be completing an end uh a task end
to end. Uh just an example, it could be
completing a task, plan, ride, test,
review as as one like workflow. Um and
another uh workflow direction could be
doing pre and
postprocessing to enhance and verify
what to enhance and verify a plan to
enhance and verify writing code testing
review or a couple or four of these or
or other parts of the software
development life cycle. And then the
last option that I suggest for a
workflow definition in our context
obviously is like covering more than one
aspect of the SDLC. It might sound like
the same as the first point, but an
end-to-end task could be for example
finishing an end toend integration test
or finishing an end to end review and
covering more than one aspect of the SLC
is like doing the testing writing code
and testing and and now because of that
that's not mutually exclusive all of
these workflows. Okay, my claim that
obviously if we want to get to the third
phase that I mentioned that you know
like a gamecher uh do a lot of coding
not necessarily in the uh ID and you
raise the quality that workflows are are
required especially in in the red team.
Okay. So, checking the time. Uh, last
last thing like to to try to uh um
visualize it. Um, now if you're trying
to do like vibe coding and you know just
like fixing a bug that something like
you just give the LLM like try to fix
it. I saw this I didn't do it like sorry
for not bringing uh credits. was hard to
find and and uh and that's what I heard
from many developers how they feel uh
you know when uh when you're trying to
vibe code generally and specifically
like fixing a bug and it could mean many
things like the bug is just waiting for
you to hit you back right so that's like
another interpretation I saw many
interpretation and then really
interestingly con continuing with with
this notion really interestingly I saw
just recently it's a few days ago go.
Karpati, the same one that coined the
term vibe coding. He wrote
that code I actually and professionally
care about. Contrast to vibe code. the
same person was in charge I think on
coining the term and getting a lot of
excitement about some of the tools and
which has a lot of it's it's really
amazing tools now thinking about it
again and he's saying that professional
code that he professionally care about I
translate that the quality is important
maintainability everything I said before
about heavy duty software that's that's
how I I take it and then he starts to
giving advice
on how to deal with it. And he gave uh
uh uh first advice advice around how to
add a lot of relevant or a lot is not
necessarily how to add uh as much as
possible or all the relevant context
that that you need to to complete. But
it's not the only thing he gave here. A
full list one, two, three, four, five,
six. And that's basically a workflow.
What he suggested is a full workflow.
And I want to focus specifically on
subworkflows around software quality and
and like bringing relevant context and
basically both of them would be around
the area of pre and postprocessing.
Okay, it's a big topic workflows and
multi- aent. I'm going to focus on pre
and pro postp processing to enhance and
verify uh uh software development in the
era of AI. So first you see the my theme
around Alice. So let's say that you want
to develop a feature and and the same
feature that you're asking for you're
probably not giving it the full spec. If
you write it all everything 100%
complete spec it's basically as writing
code. So you're probably is giving it if
you know depends on how how much do you
care about the the path you take. You're
giving it as instructions. But then even
then when you're doing vibe coding
you're letting the AI choose the path.
Now uh the thing is that one path could
be uh you know including considering SLA
architecture best practice scale spec
and the other might not. These two paths
might look the same but actually it
might look more like this like one is
leading to the castle to the feature
from behind the other is leading like
through a dangerous place etc. One
anecdote that I want to tell you that I
actually generate these these like
images uh via um a generate an image in
Google uh uh slide deck uh slides sorry
uh application. It's really really cool.
I really suggest it has some problems.
If you see here in the middle I got a
few errors quite a lot but it's still
really really awesome. So now let's
start with the software quality. So what
does it mean software quality? The
problem is that best practices and
standards etc are very different. What
happens if you have uh one 10 or or
1,000 repos and each one of them might
might or a group of them might have
different best practices. Okay. Now a
shameless plug uh for example with a
tool like merge it's one of the uh one
of the leading tools at coder that
focuses on AI code review. It can
automatically generate a best practice
markdown for you pair repo. The way it
is being it's done it's analyzing last
12 months of PR discussions and it's
also learning from interaction and
that's like what I call best uh sorry
precessing workflow before you even
generate the code before you're coming
to the code review there's a lot of work
that is being done in a very rigorous
way. It's not just like calling the LLM.
Hey, can you please go through my my PR
and and and build a best practice. It's
like more rigorous uh workflow. And you
you're you can see my talk from from
previous uh uh like uh AI native devcon
about about workflows specifically how
to build them about alpha codium etc.
And for example I wanted to use kodo or
you can use any other code generation
tool here. I'm talking about a code
review tool by Codto but you can use
code generation tool to for example add
some add some feature and in this case I
wanted to add a favicon to a chrome
extension. I wrote it in the Jira and
interestingly after I finished vibe
coding this addition I got an
interesting uh suggestion a code review
suggestion by uh uh a code of merge
saying please do not please do not link
to the asset to the image rather add it
to the to the package for me it was
surprising usually I don't want to
create big packages uh uh like for
example a chrome extension but for
because of one of the discussion we had
in the past in this chrome extension
saying that this chrome extension is
going for on-prem deployment you don't
want to link to assets outside the air
gap solution this was really exciting
and LLM could not do that without the
pre-processing that happened in in in
the past and this is just an example of
best practice that created that uh and
uh and I I know I ran quickly but I want
to cover more more area more ground this
is like uh 15 different workflows that
you can get from code emerge and one of
them is is called scan repo discussions
that creates that best practice
mark. Um that was one example of a
pre-process workflow that you could do
in order to increase uh code quality and
and put AI into work across the SDLC.
And now talk about let's talk about
bringing uh bringing uh
context. Uh so another feature the same
ticket actually was around the the same
chrome extension. It's basically a chat
interface chrome extension. Uh the
product team asked to add an
autocomplete feature. Okay, an
autocomplete feature where you do slash
you get all the commands uh of some of
one of our tools in a chat doing a slash
bring all the possible commands as
autocomplete option. Now the thing is
the Chrome extension is a front-end repo
and the commands are a back backend
repo. Okay. So what you can do
pre-process workflow okay that you can
call let's think of as like uh let's say
I'm like James Bond the let's call say
like rug multi-reaper rug okay so like
think about that pre-process as a
concept rug is basically a pre-processed
workflow that happens before you're
using the to to generate code retrieval
augmented generation and And then
there's a workflow at just in time while
you're trying to generate uh uh code or
test or or review. Okay. And it's quite
an intensive uh workflow. Here I
simplify it into uh let's say three
steps or two three steps on each part.
One, how do you turn a codebase into a
graph vector DB? And you you need to
have it in advanced workflow. For
example, language specific analysis
cloud specific. If I have a file like
basically I I have uh um a a swagger
file or I have a C++ uh like I guess C
header file. I want to treat them
differently. Hierarchal chunking etc.
And also when you're doing the retrieval
it's very different workflows workflow
to bring uh and and by the way try it
out. Try on what I'm in and one of your
favorite tool try to ask find a similar
code or find code using or find code
that does X these are very different
workflows that you need to uh to have in
order to properly do the retrieval uh uh
process. So uh by the way an anecdot if
one of you are thinking hey why not just
push everything to uh uh like an LLM
basically there's a lot of uh papers are
talking about it how it would be useful
to even if you pushing the context to an
LLM you want to order things in the
right order prioritize and organize
that's a workflow how do you organize
that and also believe me you don't want
to rely on the uh needle in the
haststack so basically uh after you do
this pre-processing uh what what you get
uh is when you're trying to vibe code uh
uh the this feature of autocomplete if
you do not use a rug pre-process and
post-process uh uh technique then you
will actually get a really good working
features you can try it in one of the
leading code generation tools but
unfortunately what's happening here is
that all of these commands that you're
seeing here on the top that we wanted to
auto to enable an autocomplete for are
not real. Most of them are actually
hallucinations. Okay. And if you do have
a proper uh uh process of of uh indexing
your codebase etc. And and that happens
let's say every night or so then you
actually can bring the relevant uh uh
the relevant like context to to bring
the relevant commands. Okay. and and
within one prompt then you can get this
result of a chat autocomplete uh for
example as a chrome extension on on your
GitHub and and and to and to finalize
and and then I'll stop and and move to
see like uh to do Q&A a bit etc. Um I I
I want to talk about like try to connect
uh connect the dots. Basically uh what
I'm saying is that the world roughly
speaking of software development divide
into let's try to define what we want to
achieve that's the spec and then we want
to implement it and then we want to uh
uh test it verify review etc and you can
have like agent assistant uh helping you
either complete chat etc but you can
also have agents and workflows I'm not
trying to differentiate here between
real workflows and agent. I'll get back
to that to do pre-processing
uh uh and and and enable you to uh have
these agent grounded and and and working
properly. That's the red team that I
talked about. But also uh you can have
dedicated workflows that helping you
transform from one to each other spec to
test spec to code. And these workflows
could be very very specific and details
and detailed. And then when you're
bringing the vibe coding and you provide
these workflows to the uh the the LLM
etc uh sorry to to the agent that is
basically an LLM that calling tools one
of the things that could happen is that
uh uh LLM is calling other uh other
workflows and agent that are more
specific more designated and then
finally you get to that uh future where
you're vi coding but with confidence and
what we're I'm trying to say here is
that a that super agent using a swarm of
agent architecture that are more
specific and based on workflows would
enable uh enable you vibe coding with
confidence but also enabling you a lot
of workflows that are outside the IDE
that you would be able for example to do
code review code testing uh code
generation uh RCA root cause root code
analysis and many other things that
you're doing as part software
development that not necessarily
happening in in the ID and that's gen
3.0 O that's the moment that we're going
to have like a full game changer and it
looks different for knobs and uh and and
uh noobs sorry and and enterprise uh for
example for for for beginners you might
get all of this wrapped for you and you
get things like bold lovable etc. And
for enterprise you might get these as
many many building blocks that you want
to play and adapt uh to your own uh
requirement. Uh so uh you know you you
can make sure that you customize it
properly for your specific SDLC uh uh
standards and uh and code and and
software development standards. So
that's it. Uh I just want to encourage
you uh to visit kodo.ai I obviously and
uh as mentioned in the beginning I'm
moving to New York and we're already
opened office there and as well in
Boston and we are hiring uh quite
aggressively. Um when you're dealing
with like serving enterprise we don't
only believe in only on chat bots uh uh
serving uh our clients. So we are hiring
also humans. So please uh please reach
out and with that uh I'll be happy uh to
answer uh
anything.
Okay. Uh do you want to like uh did you
read the Q&A? You want to offer like
specific questions
down? Oh, I don't hear you're on mute.
Thank you. Uh if if folks have any
questions, throw them in the chat. Um
and uh won't for that. There was one
that was about when you were talking uh
about with existing projects, you know,
being able to create best practices and
the like. Uh have you seen workflows as
well to be able to point to like a
golden repo or other repos in the in the
company? Um how does that work? Great
question. So, uh I I I do think that
supposedly supposedly starting from
green field is easier and for example uh
a vibe coding etc uh would uh work
wonderfully as is. And I actually uh
hinted uh strongly hinted here that you
can try to ground the vibe coding with
information that exists in the past and
you're starting with a green field. So
uh and that's maybe contradicting by the
way I do want to say that I for the time
that I had like I want to focus on one
example of workflow one example to
create best practices. Okay. But there's
many others and I really encouraging uh
u like exploring. Now uh back to the
question the I think that there's two
setups of green field. One that you're
starting a new project in an enterprise.
You probably do have from our experience
thousands if not tens of thousands if
not more of repos even if you're
starting a new project. And you want to
make sure that when you're starting a
new project you're using APIs that
already exist. you're using code that
was already verified so many times in
the past and you want to either use that
as is or be a part of the context and
inspire you to do heavy duty high
quality code even for the new project.
Okay. So even if you're starting a new
field you can still uh you still want to
use that as as context for example use
existing code and APIs or learn from
already achieved uh uh high quality
code. Now if you are starting a startup
from scratch, I want to be frank with
you just move fast and break things.
Okay? And I think like for for that uh I
I I would actually recommend using the
best practice. But you can even use the
best practice given by tools that are
building from you full website or few
products from from scratch. start from
there, you know, start
like doing that game changer products
and and and do a POV, see if it works
for you, etc. And as you go, start
bringing your best bring in your best
practices and and and knowledge into
your organization and from there you you
evolve. By the way, notice that
specifically again, sorry for the
shameless plug, we decided to use the to
have controllability and observability
around best practice. we give you as
like a file like rules files. We could
have trained a model but then you don't
see what what what actually was what's
actually learned. So this best practice
file you can uh fill it with your
specific information. You don't have to
have codo merge asking it to review past
uh uh PRs discussions or other repo etc.
you can write your own best practices
practices from scratch. Uh, okay. Thank
you. I think we're out of time. Was
really I think we got a we got a couple
minutes if if that's okay to uh we got
another uh other questions in here. So,
yeah, here we've got Min asking about
where they can find out more about all
the the Gen 3 workflows that you talked
about. Oh my god. Uh the reason uh that
I actually was a bit in a hurry is
because I'm going to a conference a live
conference to talk exactly on gen 3.0
uh.0 like workflows. So uh first of all
I
uh maybe an opportunity to say that I
try to talk about it quite a lot. Uh so
please follow me uh
itamar at x it
u mar and also um you know might do a
webinar about it. Um I think you would
if you write uh uh software uh software
3.0 for example uh you will find
interesting uh information on on Google
perplexity or or all the rest. I think
you should also write uh agents versus
workflows. Okay. And learn about that.
That's gives you a really good like
overview of what the future holds
because I actually use these two terms
inter interwe interchange between them
but they're very not very but they
actually complementary but different.
Okay. So that's my two three advice. Uh
singless plug follow me. Uh the second
read about software 3.0 and and and read
about uh workflows versus uh agents.
Sounds good. Um, and then, uh, you know,
as we get into this world where there's
a lot of extra context that's out there,
you, you know, you saw getting things
from Jira, getting things from the docs,
how have you seen people handle just
like the skew of that information? Like
code is kind of truth. It's always the
running thing. How do we handle, you
know, this this massive other context
that's out there? Yeah, if I got you
correctly like uh uh basically in
addition to code which could be massive
or very little uh very small like you
have uh uh Figma uh the technical
designs specifications for example in
Jira uh uh and and uh and and then like
I'll do shameless plug to over Tesla for
you guys like maybe you write your specs
in in Tessle uh etc and and and then you
want to absorb that. So I think there
are roughly two uh uh school of
thoughts. One just shove everything into
a context window that is growing and the
other is use advanced rug and uh then uh
the uh an agentic which is part of the
tomorrow an agentic rug uh uh ra sorry
not rug rag sorry apologize for my
accent. uh agentic rag uh would help you
uh uh m hop hop like uh on on the in
huge contexts that exist and fetch the
right one. We're very close to really
advanced technology uh there uh in in
like in Codo but other companies as well
I believe uh and and then like uh rug uh
uh is is is the future in my opinion not
not shoving everything into our context
because because of the problem of like
needle in the haststack and other thing
that I'm not sure that they're going to
be solved very soon. Yeah, I was just
there looking up the new rug acronym. I
was like I've missed another one.
There's a new a new retrieval. I have a
problem with these this acronym. No,
it's all good. Well, thank you so much.
Thank you so much for for sharing all of
that. I'm excited to learn more about
Gen 3 workflows and look forward to uh
chatting on Discord and chatting with
you more in the future. Thank you. We'll
do. Thank you so much for having me
here. It's really wonderful ecosystem.
Cheers.